Guide to An American Family DVD Collection 1973 MSS 210
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
An American Family DVD Collection
1973
MSS 210
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
0.25 linear feet (12 DVDs)
The An American Family Collection consists of 12 one-hour episodes of the 12-hour documentary, "An American Family," that debuted on PBS-TV in early 1973. It consists of 12 DVDs.
Raymond, Alan
Raymond, Susan
Arrangement note
The episodes are arranged in the order in which they originally aired on PBS-TV, 1973.
Scope and Content note
The collection is comprised of 12 one-hour episodes that document the Loud's day-to-day life during seven months of 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Material may be viewed in reading room only. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Historical Note
In 1971 filmmakers Alan and Susan Raymond spent seven months documenting the day-to-day lives of the Loud family of Santa Barbara, CA, including parents William C. “Bill” and Pat Loud and their children Lance, Kevin, Grant, Delilah, and Michele. The resulting 12-hour documentary, "An American Family," debuted on PBS-TV in early 1973. The show captivated millions of viewers worldwide with its then-unconventional depiction of middle class American family life that encompassed the "real-life drama" of marital tensions and subsequent divorce, a son's openly gay life, and the effects of the changing concepts of the American family structure. Breaking apart from the traditional American family model of harmony and ideality portrayed in fictional televison sitcoms of the early 1970s like "The Brady Bunch," the novelty and innovation of "An American Family" not only pioneered reality television, but also set the tone for the more complex family models exhibited in later shows such as "Roseanne" and "The Simpsons."
Loud Family; Loud, Lance, 1951-2001
- Series I: Videos, 1971
  - An American Family, Episode #101, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0001)
  - An American Family, Episode #102, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0002)
  - An American Family, Episode #103, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0003)
  - An American Family, Episode #104, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0004)
  - An American Family, Episode #105, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0005)
  - An American Family, Episode #106, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0006)
  - An American Family, Episode #107, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0007)
  - An American Family, Episode #108, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0008)
  - An American Family, Episode #109, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0009)
  - An American Family, Episode #110, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0010)
  - An American Family, Episode #111, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0011)
  - An American Family, Episode #112, 1971 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 210.0012)